Inventory of the Diana Mitchell Papers
Hoover Institution Archives
Diana Mitchell Papers
1953-2005
2011C36
Mitchell, Diana, 1932-
71 manuscript boxes, 3 card file boxes (29.2 linear feet)
Hoover Institution Archives Stanford, California 94305-6010
The Diana Mitchell Papers document her activities as a social and political activist, journalist, educator, and consultant in her native Zimbabwe, dating from the late 1950s to the early 2000s. The collection consists of correspondence, writings, reports, minutes, biographical data, and printed matter.
Administrative Information
Access
Collection is open for research.
The Hoover Institution Archives only allows access to copies of audiovisual items. To listen to sound recordings or to view videos or films during your visit, please contact the Archives at least two working days before your arrival. We will then advise you of the accessibility of the material you wish to see or hear. Please note that not all audiovisual material is immediately accessible.
Acquisition Information
Acquired by the Hoover Institution Archives in 2011.
Related Materials
Kent Bruce Crane Collection, Hoover Institution Archives
A. H. M. Kirk-Greene Papers, Hoover Institution Archives
H. R. G. Howman Papers, Hoover Institution Archives
Zimbabwean Subject Collection, Hoover Institution Archives
Accruals
Materials may have been added to the collection since this finding aid was prepared. To determine if this has occurred, find the collection in Stanford University's online catalog at http://searchworks.stanford.edu/. Materials have been added to the collection if the number of boxes listed in the online catalog is larger than the number of boxes listed in this finding aid.
Biographical Note
Diana Mitchell was born in Salisbury, Rhodesia (Harare, Zimbabwe), in 1932. She was a school teacher at various schools and a part-time student at the University of Zimbabwe, where she received her M.A. in African history in 1979.
During much of the late 1950s to early 2000s Mitchell lent her skills to a variety of political parties and movements, beginning in the late 1950s in Southern Rhodesia with the nascent political parties that sought to bring about a settlement between the British colonial rulers and African nationalist leaders seeking independence. After the leader of the white-minority Rhodesian Front, led by Ian Smith, declared the Unilateral Declaration of Independence (or UDI) from Britain in 1965--in its bid to maintain white minority rule in Rhodesia--Mitchell worked actively to oppose the UDI. She worked in a succession of political parties, including the United Federal Party (1957-1962), the Rhodesia Party (1963-1965), the multi-racial Centre Party (1967-1977), and its successor party, the National Unifying Force (1977-1979). In 1974 she ran as an independent candidate for parliament, campaigning to represent her home district of Highlands North in Salisbury. During this period, she also participated in a number of social programs, including ones to benefit African school children in Salisbury, and programs advocating rural development and environmental education.
Following the end of white minority rule and the independence of Zimbabwe in 1980, Mitchell continued to be active in a number of non-governmental organizations that sought to provide social services and help build the agricultural and educational infrastructure of the newly independent country. As Zimbabwean ruler Robert Mugabe tightened his grip on power through his political party, the ZANU-PF, Mitchell found herself drawn once again to organizations advocating on behalf of human rights and freedom of the press, including several political parties that were formed in opposition to the policies of the ZANU-PF, including the Forum Party in the early 1990s.
During the pre- and post-independence periods, Mitchell was also a prolific commentator on first Rhodesian, and then Zimbabwean, political and social issues, regularly publishing articles and op-ed pieces in newspapers both at home and abroad. During this period she became well-known for a series of biographical reference books on African nationalist leaders from Zimbabwe, which cemented her reputation as an expert on the political leadership of this land. During the 1990s, Mitchell was also active in the campaign to oppose the ZANU-PF's draconian laws aimed at restricting non-governmental organizations operating in the country, known as the PVO (Private Voluntary Organization) Act. In 2003, she and her husband emigrated to England, where she has continued to comment on developments in her homeland through her writings, including her online blog, "Zimbabwe?Colonial Relic" (http://z-cr.blogspot.com/).
Scope and Content of Collection
The Diana Mitchell Papers document her activities as a social and political activist, journalist, educator, and consultant in her native Zimbabwe, dating from the late 1950s to the early 2000s.
The Diana Mitchell Papers are arranged in six broad series reflecting her activities during the past fifty years. The first series, Political parties and elections file, contains correspondence, memoranda, reports, minutes of meetings, notes, voter lists, political ephemera, and related material from the parties she worked for, as well as ephemera she collected from other parties and movements. Of particular note are documents that reconstruct the founding of several political parties in Rhodesia and Zimbabwe, such as the Centre Party and Forum Party, as well as extensive material from Mitchell's own campaign for parliament. As a researcher and writer, she kept extensive subject files of newspaper clippings, documents, and ephemera, most of which are kept elsewhere in this collection. The section on "Elections," however, has been retained with this series.
The second series of materials, Civic associations and non-governmental organizations file, documents many of the organizations that Mitchell volunteered for, and in which she often played a key role, ranging from the Friends of African Schoolchildren Fund in the late 1960s up to organizations advocating human rights, freedom of the press, and the rights of women in the 1990s. Such files often contain newsletters, correspondence, financial records, printed reports, and as Mitchell served as the secretary in several of these organizations, there are extensive minutes of the meetings of such organizations. Many files from these latter years document the efforts of the ZANU-PF regime to restrict the activities of non-governmental organizations, as well as those organizations' attempts to resist such measures.
The series Academic materials and writings contains material from Mitchell's academic career, both as a graduate student at the University of Rhodesia in the 1970s, as well as her teaching career at the Harare Polytechnic Institute in the 1980s. In addition, typescripts and newspaper clippings of many of her columns and articles, primarily in Rhodesia and Zimbabwe, but also in the United Kingdom, are included. Drafts of her biographical reference books on Zimbabwean nationalist leaders are included, as is material about her long-time collaborator on this project, Robert Cary. The subseries of personal correspondence is also included in this series, and often contains reflections about the political situation in Zimbabwe written by Mitchell to friends abroad, as well as letters to Mitchell from friends within the country.
The largest series is the Subject file, which contains newspaper clippings, magazine articles, pamphlets, brochures, ephemera, and at times, correspondence, about various topics of interest to Mitchell as both an author and a political activist. Many of these files are biographical in nature, and were often used as background material for her Who's Who series on Zimbabwean political leaders. Other files are more general in scope, focusing on various social and political issues in Zimbabwe, and consist primarily of clippings taken from Rhodesian and Zimbabwean newspapers, but which sometimes contain reports, pamphlets, and other documentation. The Card file also contains biographical information and background materials for Mitchell's many projects, including the Who's Who publication.
Arrangement
The collection is organized in six groups: Political parties and elections file, Civic associations and non-governmental organizations file, Academic materials and writings, Subject file, Personal file, and Card file
Indexing Terms
The following terms have been used to index the description of this collection in the library's online public access catalog.
Zimbabwe--Politics and government.; Zimbabwe--Social conditions.; Zimbabwe--Economic conditions.
Collection Contents
- Political parties and elections file, 1956-2002 (Box 1-21:)
  Contains meeting minutes, memoranda, correspondence, flyers, pamphlets, reports, newsletters, clippings, newspapers, and photographs.
  Arranged in two groups: Political party files and Election materials. Political party files are arranged alphabetically by name of group
  - Centre Party, 1967-1987 (Folder 1-6:)
    Includes predecessor group "Moral Action Group"
    - General materials, 1968-1977 (Folder 1: 1-4)
    - Campaign materials, 1969-1980 (Folder 1: 5)
      With National Unifying Force
    - Constitution, 1968-1969 (Folder 1: 6-7)
    - Correspondence, 1968-1987 (Folder 1: 8-9)
    - Flyers and pamphlets, 1969-1973 (Folder 1: 10)
    - Individuals (Folder 1-2:)
      - Bashford, Pat, 1969-1982 (Folder 1: 11)
      - Friedman, Wendy, 1968-1979 (Folder 2: 1-5)
        Includes materials relating to Women's Section
      - Hancock, Ian R., 1978-1981, undated (Folder 2: 6)
      - McNally, Nick, 1979 (Folder 2: 7)
    - Meeting announcements, 1969-1970 (Folder 3: 8)
    - Memoranda and statements (Folder 2-3:)
      - 1974 (Folder 2: 9)
      - 1975-1977 (Folder 3: 1-4)
    - Minutes (Folder 3-4:)
      - 1967-1975 (Folder 3: 5-15)
      - 1976-1977 (Folder 4: 1-2)
    - Newsletters (Folder 4:)
      - Undated (Folder 4: 3)
      - 1969-1970 (Folder 4: 4)
      - 1973-1975 (Folder 4: 5-11)
    - Newspapers and news clippings, 1969-1976 (Folder 4: 12-16)
    - Personal file, 1971-1977 (Folder 5: 1)
      Includes political diary of Diana Mitchell
    - Photographs of party members, 1967-1970, undated (Folder 5: 2-4)
    - Posters and drawings, undated (Folder 5: 5)
    - Press releases, 1972-1974 (Folder 5: 6)
    - Race Relations in Industry and Rural Development study, 1969 (Folder 5: 7)
    - Salisbury Division, 1969 (Folder 5: 8)
    - Speeches, 1969-1972; 1977 (Folder 5: 9-10)
    - Statement of principles, 1969 (Folder 5: 11)
    - Surveys, 1967 (Folder 6: 1)
    - Women's Section (Salisbury), 1969 (Folder 6: 2)
    - Zimbabwe constitution, 1979 (Folder 6: 3)
    - Miscellaneous materials, 1978-1986 (Folder 6: 4-7)
  - Forum Party, 1992-1994 (Folder 7-10:)
    Includes material from predecessor organization, Forum for Democratic Reform. See also, Civic Associations: National Forum
    - Constitution, 1993 (Folder 7: 1-2)
    - Correspondence, 1992-1993 (Folder 7: 3)
    - Finances, 1992 (Folder 7: 4)
    - Formation (Folder 7:)
      - 1992 (Folder 7: 5)
      - 1993 (Folder 7: 6-7)
    - Founding meeting, 1993 (Folder 7: 8)
    - Launch, 1993 (Folder 7: 9)
    - Manifesto and position papers, 1993 (Folder 7: 10)
    - Meeting minutes, 1992, 1994 (Folder 7: 11)
      Includes minutes of the Electoral Supervisory Commission chaired by Bishop Peter Hatendi (1994)
    - Meetings and conventions, 1992-1993 (Folder 7: 12)
    - Memberships, 1992-1993 (Folder 8: 1-2)
    - Newsletters, 1994-1995 (Folder 8: 3)
    - Notarial deed of trust, 1992 (Folder 8: 4)
    - Papers, "Blueprint for Zimbabwe,", 1992 (Folder 8: 5)
    - Press releases, 1992-1994 (Folder 8: 6)
    - Press clippings (Folder 8-9:)
      - 1992 (Folder 8: 7-8)
      - 1993 (Folder 8: 9-10)
      - 1993 (Folder 9: 1)
      - 1994 (Folder 9: 2)
    - Publicity, 1992 (Folder 9: 3)
    - Reports, 1992-1993 (Folder 9: 4)
    - Speeches, Enoch Dumbutshena, 1992 (Folder 9: 5)
    - Statements, 1992 (Folder 9: 6)
    - Correspondence, reports, and other materials, 1992-1993 (Folder 9: 7-9)
    - Correspondence, reports, and other materials, 1992-1994 (Folder 10: 1-3)
  - Movement for Democratic Change (MDC) press clippings, manifesto, and other printed matter, 1999-2000 (Folder 10: 4-7)
  - National Unifying Force (NUF), 1977-1989 (Folder 11-12:)
    - Constitution and statement of principles, 1978 (Folder 11: 1)
    - Correspondence, 1977-1978 (Folder 11: 2-3)
    - Election campaign, 1977 (Folder 11:)
      - General, 1977 (Folder 11: 4)
      - Balloting, 1977 (Folder 11: 5)
      - Candidates, 1977 (Folder 11: 6-7)
        Includes Diana Mitchell
      - Correspondence, 1977 (Folder 11: 8)
      - Flyers and brochures, 1977 (Folder 11: 9)
      - Helpers, 1977 (Folder 11: 10)
      - Memoranda, 1977 (Folder 11: 11)
      - Opposing parties, 1977 (Folder 11: 12)
      - Press clippings, 1977 (Folder 11: 13)
      - Reports, 1978 (Folder 11: 14)
      - Speeches, 1977 (Folder 11: 15)
        Includes speeches by Allan Savory
      - Talking points, 1977 (Folder 11: 16)
      - Voter rolls, 1977 (Folder 11: 17)
    - Founding, 1977 (Folder 11: 18)
    - Meeting minutes and notes, 1977-1978 (Folder 11: 19)
    - Members, messages to, 1978-1979 (Folder 11: 20)
    - Memoranda and statements, 1978-1979 (Folder 11: 21)
    - Newsletters, 1978 (Folder 11: 22)
    - Press clippings, 1978 (Folder 12: 1)
    - Reports (Folder 12: 2)
    - Speeches, 1948 (Folder 12: 3-4)
    - Miscellany, 1979-1989 (Folder 12: 5)
  - Progressive Party correspondence, circulars, and governing documents, 1960 (Folder 12: 6-10)
  - Rhodesia Party correspondence, statement of principles, and election materials, 1963-1964 (Folder 12: 11-21)
  - Rhodesia Party memoranda, reports, and other materials, 1965-1977 (Folder 13: 1-11)
  - United Federal Party meeting minutes, newsletters, and other materials, 1956-1966 (Folder 14: 1-10)
  - United Federal Party correspondence, policies, and other materials, 1957-1961 (Folder 15: 1-2)
  - Various political parties and related materials (Folder 15-16:)
    - African National Council, 1978-1979 (Folder 15: 3)
    - Conservative Alliance, 1987; undated (Folder 15: 4)
    - Movement for Democratic Change, 2000-2002 (Folder 15: 5)
    - Rhodesian Constitutional Association, 1966-1968 (Folder 15: 6-7)
    - Rhodesian Parliament booklets, 1967-1978 (Folder 15: 8)
    - Taylor, Edna campaign materials, 1962-1965 (Folder 15: 9)
    - Zimbabwe Arts and Writers Association (ZAWA), 1979-1982 (Folder 15: 10)
    - Zimbabwe United People's Organization (ZUPO), undated (Folder 15: 11)
    - Zimbabwe Unity Movement, 1989-1990 (Folder 15: 12)
    - Materials collected by Wendy Friedman, 1978-1979 (Folder 16: 1-2)
    - Speeches, 1976-1979 (Folder 16: 3-4)
  - Elections, 1964-2002 (Folder 16-21:)
    - Voter rolls, Salisbury, various districts, 1964-1974 (Folder 16: 5-10)
    - Voter rolls, Salisbury, various districts, 1964-1974 (Contd.) (Folder 17: 1-3)
    - Diana Mitchell, candidacy for parliament seat, Highlands North (Salisbury) district, 1974 (Folder 17:)
      - Advertisements and newspapers, 1974 (Folder 17: 4-5)
      - Campaign, general, 1974 (Folder 17: 6)
      - Correspondence, 1974 (Folder 17: 7)
      - Finances, 1974 (Folder 17: 8)
      - Notes, 1974 (Folder 17: 9)
      - Opposition, Rhodesia Party and Rhodesian Front, 1974 (Folder 17: 10-11)
      - Press clippings, 1974 (Folder 17: 12)
      - Press releases, 1974 (Folder 17: 13)
      - Publicity, 1974 (Folder 17: 14)
      - Speech notes, 1974 (Folder 17: 15)
      - Voter lists (Highlands North), 1974 (Folder 17: 16)
    - General materials, 1979-2002 (Folder 18-21:)
      - 1979-1980 (Folder 18: 1-4)
      - 1985 (Folder 18: 5-10)
      - 1989-1990 (Folder 19: 1-3)
      - 1990 (Folder 19: 4-6)
      - 1990 (Contd.) (Folder 20: 1-2)
      - 1994 (Folder 20: 3-4)
      - 1995 (Folder 20: 5-9)
      - 1996 (Folder 20: 10)
      - 2000 (Folder 21: 1-4)
      - 2002 (Folder 21: 5-8)
    - Election results, 1965-1990 (Folder 21: 9)
- Civic associations and non-governmental organizations file, 1966-2005 (Box 21-30:)
  Contains newsletters, meeting minutes, flyers, pamphlets, correspondence, financial records, and clippings.
  Arranged alphabetically by name of organization
  - General, 1987-2000 (Folder 21: 10-12)
  - Association of Social Workers (Salisbury Branch), 1979 (Folder 22: 1)
  - Association of Women's Clubs, 1995-1997 (Folder 22: 2)
    See also National Women?s Council
  - Business and Professional Leaders Breakfast Club (Harare) (Folder 22:)
    - 1992-1995 (Folder 22: 3)
    - 1996-2000 (Folder 22: 4)
  - Christian Rural Development Foundation, 1975-1978 (Folder 22: 5)
  - Committee to Organize Support for a Settlement, 1972 (Folder 22: 6)
  - Ecumenical Support Services, 1997 (Folder 22: 7)
  - Foundation for Democracy in Zimbabwe (Folder 22: 8)
  - Friends of African School Children Fund, 1967-1970 (Folder 22:)
    - Correspondence, 1967-1968 (Folder 22: 9)
    - Donors, 1967; undated (Folder 22: 10)
    - Financial (Folder 22:)
      - Audits, 1968-1970 (Folder 22: 11)
      - Bank statements, 1969-1970 (Folder 22: 12)
      - Ledgers, 1967-1971 (Folder 22: 13)
      - Receipts, 1967-1971 (Folder 22: 14-18)
    - Insurance, 1969 (Folder 22: 19)
    - Minutes of meetings, 1967-1970 (Folder 22: 20)
    - Students assisted, 1967-1970 (Folder 22: 21)
    - Students assisted, 1967-1970 (Contd.) (Folder 23: 1-3)
  - Highlands African Schoolchildren's Fund, 1966-1967 (Folder 23: 4-7)
  - Highlands Ratepayers Association, 1998-2002 (Folder 23: 8-9)
  - Highlands Club Newsletter, 1992 (Folder 23: 10)
  - Institute for the Advancement of Freedom, 1998 (Folder 23: 11)
  - John Bradburne Memorial Society, 1995-2000 (Folder 24: 1-4)
    Includes interviews conducted by Diana Mitchell. See also Zimbabwe Leprosy Association
  - Konrad Adenauer Foundation (Harare branch), 1996-2002 (Folder 24: 5)
  - Mwengo (workshops for NGO activists), 1996 (Folder 24: 6)
  - National Affairs Association, 1994-1996 (Folder 24: 7)
  - National Forum, 1984-1993 (Folder 24-25:)
    - General, 1984-1988 (Folder 24: 8)
    - Income, 1985 (Folder 24: 9)
    - Meeting announcements and agenda, 1988-1993 (Folder 24: 10-11)
    - Meeting minutes, 1981-1988 (Folder 24: 12)
    - Meeting minutes, 1989-1993 (Folder 25: 1)
    - Reports, 1981-1982 (Folder 25: 2)
  - National Women's Council, 1988-1989 (Folder 25: 3)
    See also Association of Women's Clubs and Soroptimists
  - Pachipamwe International Art Workshop, 1989-1991 (Folder 25: 4)
  - Poverty Reduction Forum, 1996-1997 (Folder 25: 5)
  - Public Services Medical Aid Society, 1989-1990 (Folder 25: 6)
  - RESCU Sheltered Employment, 1989-1993 (Folder 25: 7)
  - Rhodesian Constitutional Association, 1966-1967 (Folder 25: 8)
  - Rhodesian Education Courses in Conservation and the Environment (RECCE), 1971 (Folder 25: 9-11)
  - Soroptimists International, 1990 (Folder 25: 12)
  - Streets Ahead (Folder 25-26:)
    - General, 1994-1998 (Folder 25: 13)
    - Activity reports, 1995-1998 (Folder 25: 14)
    - Budget, 1997 (Folder 25: 15)
    - Financial statements, 1995-1998 (Folder 25: 16)
    - Meeting minutes, 1995-1999 (Folder 26: 1)
    - Newsletters, 1994-1998 (Folder 26: 2)
    - Personnel, 1994-1997 (Folder 26: 3)
  - Transparency International, 1995-1996 (Folder 26: 4)
  - Voluntary Organizations in Community Enterprise (VOICE), 1976-1988 (Folder 26: 5)
  - The Whitsun Foundation, 1975 (Folder 26: 6)
  - Willie Musarurwa Memorial Trust (Folder 26-27:)
    - General, 1994-1996 (Folder 26: 7-8)
    - Awards, 1995-1996 (Folder 26: 9)
    - Brochure, undated (Folder 26: 10)
    - Correspondence, 1991-1999 (Folder 26: 11)
    - Deed of Trust, 1990-1994 (Folder 26: 12)
    - Finances, 1994-1996 (Folder 27: 1-3)
    - Fundraising, 1994-1996 (Folder 27: 4)
    - Mundawarara, Silas, obituary and condolences, 1997 (Folder 27: 5)
    - Meeting announcements, 1991-1993 (Folder 27: 6)
    - Meeting minutes (Folder 27-28:)
      - 1990-1999 (Folder 27: 7-16)
      - Miunte book, 1990-1994 (Folder 28: 1)
      - Office, 1994 (Folder 28: 2)
      - Seminars, 1993-1998 (Folder 28: 3)
      - Miscellaneous, 1994-1997 (Folder 28: 4)
      - Zimbabwe Media Council (Folder 28:)
        - Constitution and bylaws (Folder 28: 5)
        - Financial, 1992-1994 (Folder 28: 6)
        - Seminar, 1994 July 22 (Folder 28: 7)
        - Seminar, 1994 December 9 (Folder 28: 8)
  - Women for Peace, 1976-1978 (Folder 28: 9)
  - Women Voter Association of Zimbabwe, 1993-1995 (Folder 28: 10)
  - Zimbabwe Academic and Non-Fiction Writers Association, 1997-1998 (Folder 28: 11)
  - Zimbabwe Association for Crime Prevention (ZACRO), 1988-1993 (Folder 28: 12)
  - Zimbabwe-Britain Society, Harare section, 1988-2000 (Folder 28: 13-14)
  - Zimbabwe-Britain Society, Harare section, 1988-2000 (Folder 29: 1-3)
  - Zimbabwe-Britain Society, London section, 2004-2005 (Folder 29: 4)
  - Zimbabwe Rights Association, 1994-1996 (Folder 29: 5)
  - Zimbabwe International Book Fair, 1996 (Folder 29: 6)
  - Zimbabwe Leprosy Association, 1995-2002 (Folder 29: 7)
    See also John Bradburne Memorial Society
  - Zimbabwe National Chamber of Commerce, 1995 (Folder 29: 8)
  - Zimbabwe Women Finance Trust (Folder 29-30:)
    - General, 1996-1997 (Folder 29: 9)
    - Financial, 1996 (Folder 29: 10)
    - Meetings, 1996-1997 (Folder 29: 11)
    - Personnel, 1996-1997 (Folder 29: 12)
    - Publicity, circa 1996 (Folder 29: 13)
    - Publicity, circa 1996 (Folder 30: 1-2)
  - Zimbabwe Women Lawyers Association, 1999 (Folder 30: 3)
- Academic materials and writings, 1966-2000 (Box 30-38: 15)
  Contains course materials, news clippings, writings, opinion editorials, correspondence, and serial monographs.
  Arranged in three groups: Universities and technical institutes, Writings, and Correspondence
  - Universities and technical institutes, 1973-1984 (Folder 30-34:)
    - University of Rhodesia, Master's Degree program, 1973-1979 (Folder 30: 4-7)
    - University of Rhodesia, Master's Degree program, 1973-1979 (Contd.) (Folder 31: 1-7)
    - University of Rhodesia, Master's Degree program, 1979 (Folder 32: 1-2)
    - Harare Polytechnic lesson plans, curriculum, readings, teaching materials, 1966-1977 (Folder 32: 3-5)
    - Harare Polytechnic lesson plans, curriculum, readings, teaching materials, 1981-1983 (Folder 33: 1-8)
    - Harare Polytechnic lesson plans, curriculum, readings, course descriptions, 1981-1984 (Folder 34: 1-6)
  - Writings, 1961-2000 (Folder 35-38:)
    - Newspaper articles, op-ed columns, and other writings, 1961-1998 (Folder 35: 1-11)
      Includes columns under the pseudoym "Mwana Wevhu"
    - "A Dictionary of Politics in Zimbabwe" proposal, 1991 (Folder 36: 1)
    - Who's Who: African Nationalist Leaders in (Rhodesia) Zimbabwe, various editions, 1974-1983 (Folder 36-38:)
      - General, 1975 (Folder 36: 2)
      - 1977 edition, one volume, co-authored with Robert Cary (Folder 36: 3)
      - 1980 edition (Folder 36: 4)
      - 1981-1982 edition (Folder 36: 5)
      - 1982-1983 supplement (Folder 36: 6)
      - Cary, Robert (Folder 36:)
        - Correspondence with, 1974-1977 (Folder 36: 7)
        - Correspondence about, 1977-1978 (Folder 36: 8)
        - Documents about Cary, 1977-1978; undated (Folder 36: 9)
        - News clippings, 1975-1978 (Folder 36: 10)
        - Tributes by Diana Mitchell, 1977 (Folder 36: 11)
        - Writings by Cary, 1975-1977 (Folder 36: 12)
      - Correspondence, general, 1976-1988 (Folder 37: 1)
      - Correspondence, publishers, 1974-1981 (Folder 37: 2)
      - Expenses, 1973-1978 (Folder 37: 3)
      - Jacket designs, 1977-1983 (Folder 37: 4)
      - Orders, 1980-1984 (Folder 37: 5-9)
      - Publicity, 1977-1981 (Folder 37: 10)